

Francisco Caro Diaz
Mobile: 658859892 Phone: 955280492
franciscocarodiaz@gmail.com
Web: http://franciscocarodiaz.github.io
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/franciscocarodiaz
GitHub: https://github.com/franciscocarodiaz
Skype: carodiazfrancisco

Francisco Caro Díaz

Mobile and Web Software Engineer

Diploma in Technical Engineering in Computer Systems Engineering degree in Computer Science and two master conducted by the University of Seville: the first "E-Learning" and the second "Web and Mobile Application Development." I have work experience as a developer, tester and project manager for Web applications and mobile devices.

I have good experience in dealing in many international projects, I have good knowledge on overall businesses that may be of your interest. I have social skills and competences I think with the power and ability to work in teams. I am an open person and entrepreneur who likes new challenges and working hard to achieve their goals. I consider myself tenacious, hardworking and restless eager to learn each day and grow personally and professionally.

I love the world of mobility and every day my interest is higher, and therefore try to learn and renew my knowledge day by day. I try to guide my career on projects both Android, iOS, hybrid mobile development technologies and wearable projects and I've always had a passion for it, also because I think it is not our future if it's our present.

Working for more than three years for an international company in several international projects like the Olympics Games or Airbus, I have obtained various capacities and professional skills:

- High level of responsibility, organization, planning and supervision.
- Ability to communicate and listen.
- Perseverance and constancy of purpose, both individually and as a team.
- Agile methodology for achieving results in the short, medium and long term and quality.
- Analytical capacity for decision-making.
- Entrepreneurial spirit, fostering creativity and initiative.
- Experience with project management.
- Flexibility, mobility. Open to other cultures and the use of new technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fecha: March 2015 – May 2015.

Empresa: Infantium.

<u>Puesto Ocupado</u>: Senior Mobile developer.

Descripción: Responsible development new application of Infantium working with iOs and Android.

Fecha: January 2015 – February 2015.

Empresa: Celeris Mobile Solutions S.L.

Puesto Ocupado: Senior Mobile developer.

<u>Descripción:</u> Responsible of development project for iPad working with Swift for project Emoiste.

<u>Date</u>: April 2014 – October 2014. Company: InvierteMe-Ventures.

Role: Software Engineer and Project Manager in projects for web and mobile platform.

Summary: Mobile Engineer in InvierteMe Ventures. Responsible of development of the mobile application

Klifik. The main assigned challenge was achieved: launch application on the three platforms:

web, android and ios.

Tecnologies: Android, Objective-C, SQLite, PHP, JSON, SVN, Git, HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript.

Url Google Play: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.klifik.klifik

<u>Url Apple Store:</u> http://appstore.com/klifik

<u>Date</u>: September 2011 - Currently.

Company: Freelance

Role: Android-iOs developer.

Summary: Participation in various projects with iOs and Android technology.

- 1. Mobile and Wearables projects. I have organized and work in several projects related to mobile + wearables technology. You could check part of the code of many of the functionalities that I have developed in my personal repository.
- 2. Apple Watch. RedKitt, Redbooth WatchKith Hackaton. Hackathon organized by RedBooth in Barcelona. The objective was to use the Redbooth API and design something using it. RedKitt is an app to do a meaningful task management taking advantage of the core concept of Redbooth. Winners of "The best use of the Redbooth API",

Link to source code.

3. Android and iOS App for the Seville European Film Festival. SEFF2013 SEFF2012 and applications were developed for the 2012 edition and 2013 European Film Festival in Seville. For the last edition as an official developer also participated in the design and iOs application development.

The purpose of this app was to give everyone attending the festival a new way to access all your channels and services: news blog, youtube channel, image gallery from Picasa, using maps to show performances and cinemas, detailed listing and description of all the films presented showing them by category or by day of the festival.

Google Play: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arequa.seff2013 Apple Store:

https://itunes.apple.com/es/app/festival-cine-europeo-sevilla/id735322132?mt=8

4. Android App for the group of carnival "Vendedores de Humo". VH2014 is the application with all the content related to a group of carnival Conil de la Frontera.

In this application you can see the lyrics of their songs, listen to songs, watch videos from your YouTube channel , view the entire collection of images from performances , locate on a map the next steps and how to get there .

Google Play: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arequa.vh2014

5. Other Android applications. I have developed more native applications for Android but currently not on Google Play as they are in the final stage of production, including one dedicated to selling through mobile products shop, another app made by the University of Sevilla for the management of library staff and other integrated learning system to perform different courses through mobile mLearning application: integrating video, surveys and all documents management, registration and payment.

<u>Date</u>: April 2013 – April 2014.

Company: Atos, Sevilla.

Role: Software Engineer in project Bundle ECM-Search Component.

<u>Summary:</u> IT project for Airbus where we offer different services: Vivisimo Java developer, server process

monitoring, project management consulting, Projects and Development, for different platforms

Airbus: Airbus World, People and Airbus Airbus Supply.

Date: September 2012- April 2013.

Company: Atos, Sevilla.

Main Activity: Software developer in Project NOS SEUR.

<u>Summary:</u> Technological renovation project of the entire operating system initially decentralized SEUR for

each franchise, gathering all information and operating in the same DB Seur working with web technologies: framework SEAM, JSF RichFaces, Ajax, javascript, CSS, data processing specifications XML and JSON, transformation and presentation for XML document: XSL Transformations (XSLT) and the XML Path Language (XPath), EJB 3.0, Hibernate (JPA), Oracle.

Date: October 2011- September 2012.

Company: Atos, Sevilla.

Role: Tester project Olympics Games London 2012.

<u>Summary:</u> Design, analysis and testing in information difussion systems (INFO) and the Commentator

Information System (CIS).

Date: March 2011- October 2011.

Company: Atos, Sevilla.

Role: Tester project KPN Belgium.

Summary: Design, analysis and testing of new functionality in systems leading provider of telephony, data

and Internet. Temporary collaboration in other projects: Euskaltel, analyst Billing System

Upgrade.

Date: March 2008- September 2008.

<u>Company:</u> Sadiel, Sevilla.

<u>Role:</u> Software developer.

<u>Summary:</u> Design and develop with open ESB tool using NetBeans IDE as a development environment and

deployed to the GlashFish server, exposing a web service on the bus, database processing using binding components, HTTP BC, BC JDBC, BPEL processes. Creating an EJB module. OpenESB on JBoss study. Creating WebServices with an EJB module using Java as a language to process data

from an Oracle database.

EDUCATION

Technical Engineering in Computer Systems.

University of Sevilla. 2003-2007.

Degree in Computer Engineering.

University of Sevilla. 2008 - 2011.

Scolarship Erasmus during 11 months in Genova (Italy).

2009-2010.

CERTIFICATIONS AND ACCREDITATIONS

Digital Marketing

Google - IAB Spain - University of Seville (December 2014).

iOS Mobile Development Bootcamp Barcelona

IronHack, Oct - November 2014

400+ hours with fundamentals of Objective-C, CocoaTouch and Xcode, interface design, networking and memory management:

- The basics: Objective-C, Xcode and interface builder, Swift, Simple memory management, test specs with XCUnit, Cocoa Pods.
- Coding: MVC pattern, Controllers, Simple views, Views, Custom views and drawing, Simple animations, Autolayout, Touches and gestures.
- Persistent apps: Models, Basic persistence, Basic networking, Threads and concurrency.
- Testing focus: Advanced persistence (Core Data), Advanced testing (Kiwi, Expecta), Functional testing (KIF).
- Advanced: Core Graphics and Animations, Location, Advanced networking, Debugging, Profiling.

- Online course Developing iOS 7 APPS FOR IPHONE AND IPAD.

University of Standford (Febrary 2011 - Currently).

CERTIFICATION VIVISIMO VELOCITY PLATFORM AND IBM InfoSphere Data Explorer.

IBM - Atos Toulouse (Abril 2013).

MASTER DEGREE In Developing applications for Internet and mobile devices.

University of Sevilla (20/10/2011 - 17/08/2012).

- JAVA: UML, Architecture JavaSE y JavaEE, Application Client/Server, Design Patterns : MVC,UI.
- DESIGN AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT DATABASE WITH ORACLE: SQL Language. Oracle, JDBC, Hibernate, JPA.
- INTERNET APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT: Web Design. XHTML, CSS, Applets, Javascript, AJAX, XML, web server development: Servlets and Java Server Pages (JSP), Notation JSON, Web Development Frameworks: Struts JavaServer Jaces (JSF), EJB.
- BASED APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT SERVICES: Web Services: SOA Service Oriented Architecture, Web services development with JAX-WS, JAXB, using public web services (Google, Facebook, Twitter, etc.), Cloud Computing, Green Computing.
- Development and deployment of mobile applications: JavaME, Android using Java language, Windows Phone 7 using Framework. Net, iOS 4 (iPhone, iPad) Objective-C.
- Interactivity in new applications: multi-touch screens, widget, gadget, widget / gadget, IP interactive TV.

- MASTER DEGREE IN E-LEARNING: NEW TECHNOLOGIES FOR LEARNING THROUGH INTERNET.

University of Sevilla (1/10/2010 - 10/07/2011).

- Technological platforms for e-Learning.
- Designing training through technological platforms.
- Learning Processes in e-learning.
- Design pedagogical training to e-Learning.
- Web design for e-Learning (Exe-learning).
- Usability and accessibility to e-Learning.
- Graphic design for e-Learning (Adobe Photoshop).
- Tools 2.0 for e-learning.
- Environment of the organizations with e-Learning.
- New Trends in e-Learning: m-learning.

- Course Application Development J2ME Java for Mobile Devices. *University of Murcia* (10/02/2011 - 10/05/2011).

Course object oriented programming with Java.

University of Sevilla - Atos. (10/01/2011 - 10/03/2011).

- Course website design based on Content Management Systems (CMS)

University of Sevilla - Atos. (22/11/2007 - 06/12/2007). Web services, Mysql y phpMyAdmin, Joomla, Drupal,wikis, zopeplone

KNOWLEDGE AND LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Upper-Intermediate.

ITALIAN: ADVANCED

11 months in Genova ,Italy.

FRENCH: Intermediate

4 months in Toulouse ,France.